Register of the Joseph Warren Stilwell papers 51001
Hoover Institution Archives
- Personal and Family File, 1889-1972
  - B-1, 1889-1931
    - Letters
      - Unidentified; undated letter from Benjamin W. Stilwell to his family, 1899-1902 (Box-folder 55: 9)
        Letter of recommendation for Joseph W. Stilwell from the principal of his high school, 1899; letter from Benjamin W. Stilwell to Joseph Stilwell, 1900; and letter to Mrs. Benjamin W. Stilwell, 1902
      - Transcribed letters from Joseph W. Stilwell to his family and notes on his athletic activities at West Point, 1900-1904 (Box-folder 55: 10)
    - Notification from the Adjutant General's Office, U.S. War Dept., to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1900 (Box-folder 55: 11)
      Report for examination to determine his qualifications for appointment as a cadet of the Military Academy.
    - Proof of citizenship issued by the U.S. Dept. of State to Benjamin W. Stilwell and family, 1889 (Box-folder 55: 12)
    - Miscellany, 1889-1899 (Box-folder 55: 13)
      Includes copy of will of Nicholas Stilwell.
  - B-2, 1901-1972
    - Agreement with the New York Life Insurance Company, 1905 (Box-folder 55: 14)
    - Ancestral records, 1902 (Box-folder 55: 15)
    - Army records, including circulars, 1902-1907 (Box-folder 55: 16)
    - Certificates of completion of various courses, 1905 (Box-folder 55: 17)
    - Clipping announcing the beginning of preliminary training for the Army's football team and referring to the assistance of Joseph W. Stilwell during the last two seasons, undated (Box-folder 55: 18)
    - Correspondence with U.S. War Dept., and others, and postcards sent to Mrs. Benjamin W. Stilwell and Joseph W. Stilwell, 1904-1911 (Box-folder 55: 19)
    - List of officers, 1905 (Box-folder 55: 20)
    - Manuscript by Joseph W. Stilwell, Army Basketball at West Point from Its Inception, 1972 July 27 (Box-folder 55: 21)
      Includes letter from William A. Knowlton to Ernest F. Easterbrook.
    - Notes, including of Guatemala trip and of homework for class in Spanish, 1901 (Box-folder 55: 22)
    - Record of service, 1906-1909 (Box-folder 55: 23)
    - Miscellany, 1904-1914 (Box-folder 55: 24)
  - B-3, 1962
    - Clippings, undated (Box-folder 55: 25)
    - Correspondence between Joseph W. Stilwell, Jr., and Armand Belhomme and Richard Blum, Jr., 1962 January–February (Box-folder 55: 26)
    - Identification card from U.S. War Dept., 1917 (Box-folder 55: 27)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 55: 28)
    - Telegrams, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 55: 29)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 55: 30)
  - B-5, 1917-1919
    See also PHOTOGRAPHS, box 85, folder 1.
    - Application for patent from John W. Smith for new and useful improvement in cartridge-feed mechanism for firearms, 1919 May 13 (Box-folder 56: 1)
    - Notes, 1917 (Box-folder 56: 2)
    - Postcard, 1918 (Box-folder 56: 3)
  - B-8, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 56: 4-10)
    Materials for Chinese language study, including lists of words and phrases with some English translation, selected lists of characters, lists of questions, phonetic picture dictionary, and examination in Elementary Chinese.
  - B-9, 1930-1934
    - Letters, including to Mrs. Joseph W. Stilwell, 1930-1934 (Box-folder 56: 7)
    - Notebook with miscellaneous information, undated (Box-folder 56: 8)
      Including accounting records, chronological record of Joseph W. Stilwell's school years, dates of land and sea crossings, personal characteristics and sayings, Smith family tree, and Stilwell family tree and notes.
  - B-11, 1939
    See also PHOTOGRAPHS, box 96, folder 1.
    - Correspondence, 1939 (Box-folder 56: 9-11)
      Includes letters of congratulations.
    - Telegrams, 1939 (Box-folder 56: 12)
  - B-12, 1940-1941
    See also Photographs/DD.
    - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 56: 13)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 56: 14)
  - B-13, 1942-1943
    See also PHOTOGRAPHS, box 96, folder 3.
    - Cartoons, undated (Box-folder 56: 15)
    - Letters, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 56: 16)
      Including from the Viceroy’s office, New Delhi, India, undated; Henry L. Stimson, January 6, 1943; Brehon Somervell, March 10, 1943; and Richard B. Russell, September 1, 1943. Includes letters from the Chief of Staff, U.S. War Dept., to Mrs. Joseph W. Stilwell, May 5 and 22, 1942, and from Madame Chiang Kai-shek to Olive Monroe c/o Mrs. Joseph W. Stilwell, November 11, 1942.
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 56: 17)
  - B-14, 1910-1944
    - Charts, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 57: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Box-folder 57: 2-4)
      Including letters of congratulations for receiving the Fourth Star.
    - Notes on a conference with President Franklin D. Roosevelt and Harry Hopkins on policy in China, Cairo, Egypt, 1943 December 6 (Box-folder 57: 5)
    - Outline of training plan for Z-Force Divisions, 1944 (Box-folder 57: 6)
    - Telegrams, 1943 (Box-folder 57: 7)
    - Writings, undated
      - "Deckhand Diplomat," chapter of an unidentified book, undated (Box-folder 57: 8)
      - "Stilwell: Descendants of Charles Oliver Stilwell," reprint from vol. VII of Men of Mark in Georgia, W. J. Northen, ed., 1910-1944 (Box-folder 57: 9)
        Includes Joseph W. Stilwell's letter to Laura K. Wallace, December 29, 1944.
    - Miscellany, 1944 (Box-folder 57: 10)
  - B-15, 1945
    - Contract for purchase of manuscript, Message to G.I. Joe, 1945 September 19 (Box-folder 57: 11)
      See also INCREMENTAL MATERIALS, box 105, folder 6.
    - Correspondence, 1945 February 23 (Box-folder 57: 12-14)
      Including a letter from Paul North Rice to Joseph W. Stilwell, New York Public Library, January 5, 1945, relating to the four-volume set of the Genealogy of the Stilwell Family, privately published, 1929-1930; and letters from Joseph W. Stilwell to Louis Mountbatten and John N. Wheeler.
    - Memoranda, 1945 (Box-folder 57: 15)
    - Telegrams, 1945 (Box-folder 57: 16)
  - B-16, 1945
    See also PHOTOGRAPHS, box 96, folder 4.
    - Letters, including to Frank Merrill, George Patton, and Eleanor Roosevelt, 1945 (Box-folder 57: 17-19)
    - Memoranda, 1945 (Box-folder 57: 20)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 57: 21)
  - B-17, 1945
    - Clippings, 1945 (Box-folder 58: 1)
    - Correspondence, including with John P. Davies, 1945 (Box-folder 58: 2-3)
    - Memoranda, 1945 (Box-folder 58: 4)
    - Telegrams and messages, 1945 (Box-folder 58: 5)
  - B-18, 1945
    - Clippings and printed matter, 1945 (Box-folder 58: 6)
      Including excerpts of congratulatory messages from Dwight D. Eisenhower to E. F. Reinhardt and O. N. Bradley, and excerpts of Joseph W. Stilwell's remarks for Nisei troops.
    - Correspondence, including with Hugh de Lacy, 1945 (Box-folder 58: 7-9)
    - Miscellany, 1945 (Box-folder 58: 10)
  - B-19, 1942-1946
    - Biographical sketches, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 58: 11)
      Including from 1942 Yearbook, 1942-1946, and news release,
    - Correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 58: 12-14)
    - Letters of condolences on the death of Joseph W. Stilwell from Dwight D. Eisenhower, Hugh de Lacy, and others., 1946 (Box-folder 58: 15)
      See also Incremental Materials, Correspondence.
    - Speeches, 1946, undated
      - Chester W. Nimitz and Joseph W. Stilwell, Boy Scouts of America, undated (Box-folder 58: 16)
        Printed copy.
      - Joseph W. Stilwell, announcement in The Business Woman, 1946 September 17 (Box-folder 58: 17)
    - Telegrams, 1946 (Box-folder 58: 18)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 58: 19)
  - B-20, 1919-1941
    - Circulars, 1927-1941 (Box-folder 58: 20)
    - Clippings, 1931 (Box-folder 58: 21)
    - Letters of appreciation and transfer, 1919-1927 (Box-folder 58: 22)
    - Memoranda, including award of Distinguished Service Medal, 1942 October 14 (Box-folder 58: 23)
      Includes a message of appreciation for distinguished service, October 14, 1942.
    - Telegrams, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 58: 24)
  - B-21, 1919-1950
    - Certificates, including of satisfactory completion of various subjects at the Command and General Staff School, 1919-1947 (Box-folder 58: 25)
    - Circulars, 1949 (Box-folder 58: 26)
    - Citations, undated (Box-folder 58: 27)
    - Letters to Mrs. Joseph W. Stilwell and to Joseph W. Stilwell, Jr., 1946-1949 (Box-folder 58: 28)
      Commendations and awards of medals, and personal letters of remembrance and admiration.
    - List of decorations awarded to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942-1950 (Box-folder 58: 29)
    - Memoranda, 1919-1949 (Box-folder 58: 30)
    - Program for dedication of Stilwell Dam and Stilwell Lake, 1949 (Box-folder 58: 31)
  - B-22, 1927-1965
    - General, undated (Box-folder 59: 1)
    - Financial records, 1942-1958 (Box-folder 59: 2)
    - Introduction of Joseph W. Stilwell by Prentiss M. Brown, Annual Meeting, Michigan Post Army Ordnance Association, 1945 May 16 (Box-folder 59: 3)
    - Notarized copy attesting to the birth of Joseph W. Stilwell, 1927 (Box-folder 59: 4)
    - Passport, 1935 (Box-folder 59: 5)
    - Personal letters of remembrance and admiration, 1965 (Box-folder 59: 6)
- Literary File, 1907-1946
  Articles, essays, lyrics, notes, poems, sketches, and speeches, arranged numerically by file numbers and alphabetically by physical form thereunder.
  - C-1
    - Lecture notebook, undated (Box-folder 59: 7)
    - Notes, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 59: 8)
  - C-2
    - Articles
      - ["Linyl"], undated (Box-folder 59: 9)
      - "Psychology of the Chinese,", undated (Box-folder 59: 10)
        Holograph fragment.
      - "Strategic Features of China,", undated (Box-folder 59: 11)
      - "Tienchiachen Battle,", undated (Box-folder 59: 12)
      - Untitled, 1938 (Box-folder 59: 13)
        Holograph and typescript.
    - Christmas issue of the Bulletin, G2–4th Corps, illustrating Joseph W. Stilwell's expressions towards the infantrymen, 1918 (Box-folder 59: 14)
    - Speeches, 1946, undated
      - Cleveland, Ohio, undated (Box-folder 59: 15)
      - Independence Day broadcast, Radio Okinawa, undated (Box-folder 59: 16)
      - Interview of Joseph W. Stilwell by an unidentified G.I., undated (Box-folder 59: 17)
      - Appreciation Banquet, J.A.C.L., San Francisco, California, 1946 May 7 (Box-folder 59: 18)
  - C-3, Articles and other writings
    - Untitled fragments, undated (Box-folder 59: 19)
    - "America's Eastern Question,", undated (Box-folder 59: 20)
    - "China,", undated (Box-folder 59: 21)
    - "The Chinese Situation,", undated (Box-folder 59: 22)
    - "Evolution of Modern China,", undated (Box-folder 59: 23)
      Holograph.
    - Foreword to "China for Player and Spectator?,", undated (Box-folder 59: 24)
    - Notes for a speech?, undated (Box-folder 59: 25)
    - "The Chinese-Japanese War of 1894-1895,", 1920 (Box-folder 59: 26)
    - Untitled fragment, circa 1927-1928 (Box-folder 59: 27)
    - "The Mongol Invasion of Japan,", circa 1935 (Box-folder 59: 28)
    - Outline of a chapter?, 1937 (Box-folder 59: 29)
    - "On Chinese Battles,", 1938 (Box-folder 59: 30)
    - Untitled, 1938 October 23-28 (Box-folder 59: 31)
  - C-4, Articles and other writings
    - Untitled poem (Box-folder 59: 32)
    - "The Cruise of the 'Irish Stew',", untitled (Box-folder 59: 33)
    - "Estáln saltando,", untitled (Box-folder 59: 34)
    - "The Fighting Demon,", undated (Box-folder 59: 35)
    - "Mexico,", undated (Box-folder 59: 36)
    - "Riding the Tiger," musical performance, Fort Benning, Georgia, undated (Box-folder 59: 37)
      Typescript lyrics.
    - "Short History of Germany,", undated (Box-folder 59: 38)
    - "Lecture on Guatemala,", 1907, undated (Box-folder 60: 1)
      Includes a letter and a report from Joseph W. Stilwell to the Chief of the 2nd Division, General Staff, 1907. Typescript.
    - "Military Services and Sufferings of the Colonel of Cavalry Jose Maria Hunter,", 1909 (Box-folder 60: 2)
      Translated by Joseph W. Stilwell from Spanish to English, 1909. Typescript.
  - C-5, Miscellaneous writings
    - Article by Galoola Vinegaritch, "Anemian Nights,", undated (Box-folder 60: 3)
    - Notes and writings by Joseph W. Stilwell, 1924-1946 (Box-folder 60: 4)
- Clippings and Printed Matter, 1899-1971
  See also: Box 111, folders 1-6.
  - Before 1941 (Box-folder 60: 5-7)
  - 1941 (Box-folder 60: 8)
  - 1942 (Box-folder 60: 9-15)
  - 1943 (Box-folder 60: 16-18)
  - 1944 (Box-folder 61: 1-10)
  - Joseph W. Stilwell's recall, 1944 October–November (Box-folder 61: 11-14)
  - 1945 (Box-folder 62: 1-7)
  - 1946 (Box-folder 62: 8-17)
  - 1947 (Box-folder 63: 1)
  - Reviews of The Stilwell Papers, arranged and edited by Theodore H. White, with a foreword by Winifred A. Stilwell, 1948 April-May (Box-folder 63: 2-15)
    Includes letters from Beatrice B. Gould and Frank Dorn to Winifred Stilwell and a photo layout for the book.
  - Reviews of The Stilwell Papers, 1948 (Box-folder 64: 1-6)
  - 1949 (Box-folder 64: 7)
  - 1950 and after (Box-folder 64: 8-12)
  - Reviews of Stilwell and the American Experience in China by Barbara Tuchman, 1971 January 21 (Box-folder 64: 13)
    Includes a letter from Mathew B. Ridgeway to Barbara Tuchman.
  - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 64: 14-17)
- Annotated Maps, 1908-1945
  See also: Oversize Materials.
  - Anti-Communist campaign in Shansi and West China, 1935-1936 (Map-case folder 17)
    Government and communist forces.
  - China-Burma-India Theater, undated (Map-case folder 18)
  - Europe, undated (Map-case folder 19)
  - Northern Expedition, 1926, 1945 (Map-case folder 20)
    Forces of the central government and of Chiang Kai-shek, Okinawa Island, (island fortifications).
  - Sino-Japanese conflict, 1937-1939 (Map-case folder 21)
    Movements of Chinese army, map of Beijing, map of city of Manila, state of Mexico, and map of railroads.
- Miscellany, 1910-1946
  Articles, handbook, notebook, notes, pamphlets, and printed matter relating to the activities of the U.S. Army, arranged alphabetically by physically form.
  - Article, "The Story of White Sands Proving Ground,", 1946 April 30 (Box-folder 65: 1)
  - Army Ground Force Equipment Review Board file
    - Part I, Board study and annexes, undated (Box-folder 65: 2)
    - Part II, Enclosures, undated (Box-folder 65: 3)
  - Handbooks entitled "Tactical Principles and Decisions," General Service Schools, Fort Leavenworth, Kansas, 1925 (Box-folder 65: 4)
  - Notebook kept by Joseph W. Stilwell while Military Attaché in Peking, 1935-1939 (Box-folder 65: 5)
  - Notebooks for Chinese language practice, undated (Box-folder 65: 6)
  - Notes, circa 1935-1946 (Box-folder 65: 7)
  - Pamphlets, 1910, undated
    - Communism or Sanity in Government: An American Solution, by Jay Taylor, undated (Box-folder 65: 8)
    - Art of War, by Sun Tzu, 1910 (Box-folder 65: 9)
  - U.S. War Dept. Equipment Board file
    - Agenda for hearings, undated (Box-folder 66: 1)
    - Handbook, undated (Box-folder 66: 2)
    - Notebook, undated (Box-folder 66: 3)
- Memorabilia, 1889-1946
  Joseph W. Stilwell's personal effects, gifts, and some souvenirs from the army, arranged alphabetically by physical form within each box.
  - Army IV Corps banner (Box 67)
  - Army ground forces patch (Box 67)
  - Copper etching of Joseph W. Stilwell (Box 67)
  - House plaque - Military Attaché (Box 67)
  - Ramgarh Training Center cap, 1943 (Box 67)
  - Sweater and cadet hat from West Point (Box 67)
  - Trophy with the engraving (Box 67)
    "General Stilwell, C-In-C of Chinese Army in India, Graduates of Tactical School, Ramgarh Training Center, U.S. Army in India, Burma, and China, 1943"
  - Wood carving portrait of Joseph W. Stilwell (Box 67)
  - Wooden replica of a plane, 1946 May 10 (Box 67)
  - Miscellany (Box 67)
  - Hat of Joseph W. Stilwell, Jr., from West Point (Box 68)
  - Officer’s cape and vest of Joseph W. Stilwell (Box 68)
  - Miscellaneous service and award ribbons and other personal effects (Box 68)
  - Caps, including Four-Star overseas cap (Box 69)
  - Merrill’s Marauders trial insignia (Box 69)
  - Military wristwatch and watch box (Box 69)
  - Personal effects of Joseph W. Stilwell, including arm band, belt buckle, cadet insignia, hat bands, leather belt with purses, ribbons, shoulder bag and epaulettes for formal uniform, various name plates, and others (Box 69)
  - U.S. flag (Box 69)
  - World War I name plates, G-1 Army IV Corps (Box 69)
  - Wooden box used to carry wine in Joseph W. Stilwell's plane (Box 70)
  - Sleeping bag (Box 71)
  - Calligraphed Chinese scroll (Box 72)
  - Canadian Medical Association medal (Box 72)
  - Canvas covering for a flag (Box 72)
  - Cartoon depicting Joseph W. Stilwell (Box 72)
  - China-Burma-India Theater insignia (Box 72)
  - Combat infantryman's badge presented to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1946 October 11 (Box 72)
  - Four-Star insignia (Box 72)
  - Japanese battle flag with names of people in the organization (Box 72)
  - Mementos from China (Box 72)
  - Novelli Award for Distinguished Service and 1905 award from the Philippines (Box 72)
  - Poem by J. W. Wright entitled "Outward Bound," attached to a photograph of a ship sailing, printed on hand-made paper by the craftsmen of the Press in the Forest, Carmel, California, undated (Box 72)
  - Pistol belt (Box 72)
  - Tribute to Joseph W. Stilwell from the Chinese people, 1942 (Box 72)
  - White Star Medal, 1948 (Box 72)
  - Miscellany, insignias, medals, ribbons, patches, postcards, and service badges, 1889 (Box 72)
    Includes items from the Exposition Universelle, Paris.
  - Banner (Box 73)
  - Ceramic plate, 1904, undated (Box 73)
    Memento of the 1904 exposition in St. Louis, Missouri, attended by Joseph W. Stilwell on horseback with his West Point cavalry team.
  - G-2 IV Army Corps bullet (Box 73)
  - Various cards, train tickets, music card, postcards including from France and Germany, and personal stamp (Box 73)
  - Military jacket (Box 74)
  - Ashtray with a 50-caliber swag (Memorabilia cabinet)
  - Two-Star overseas cap from Joseph W. Stilwell's days in Fort Ord, California (Memorabilia cabinet)
  - West Point hat from Cadet Quarter Master Department and cadet bathrobe (Memorabilia cabinet)
- Oversize Materials, 1904-1945
  Cartoons, certificates, diagrams, diplomas, drafts of various documents, letters, maps, and posters, arranged alphabetically by physical form within each folder.
  - Cartoons entitled "Down to Earth," "The Great Otto Schmeercase," "Guardians of the West," and "On the Wings of Victory,", undated (Map-case folder 1)
  - Certificate of membership in The Empire State Society issued to Joseph W. Stilwell by the Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, 1907 November 1 (Map-case folder 1)
  - Diploma recommending Joseph W. Stilwell for promotion in the U.S. Army, 1904 June 15 (Map-case folder 1)
  - Maps (Map-case folder 1)
    - Belgium, France, Germany, and Switzerland, IV Army Corps, undated
      See also box 11, folder 7.
    - Operations, Northern Combat Area Command, 1943 October – 1945 April (Map-case folder 1)
  - Posters (Map-case folder 1)
    - Chinese nationalist leaders, undated
    - "Good-luck" poster for the American soldiers in the Philippines signed by some of them at the back, 12th Infantry, Camp Jossman, Philippine Islands, 1905 October
  - Document entitled "Surrender," based on the executive order of the Imperial Japanese Government issued at Yokohama, September 2, 1945, for the surrender of the Islands in the Ryukyus, signed by Joseph W. Stilwell (Map-case folder 2)
  - Draft of handwritten ultimatum entitled "The Twenty-One Demands" (revised April 26, 1945), presented May 1 and accepted May 8, 1945 (Map-case folder 2)
    Includes clippings relating to the Monroe Doctrine, July 4, 1931.
  - Letter with a good-bye message to Joseph W. Stilwell from an unidentified individual on the eve of Joseph W. Stilwell’s departure, April 27, 1918 (Map-case folder 2)
  - Maps (Map-case folder 2)
    - Map-overlay device used by Joseph W. Stilwell in intelligence operations during World War I
    - Maps and sketches detailing airplane course record, patrol record, and shelling record, undated
    - Maps of the China-Burma-India Theater
    - Maps of Yellow River Road, Shansi, China, undated
    - Maps of World War I battle lines, 1917-1918 (Map-case folder 3-4)
  - German battle orders, undated (Map-case folder 5)
    Index attached.
  - Diagrams of trench networks, tunnels, dugout, pillboxes, and other fortified structures, prepared by the U.S. Army IV Corps, G-2, 1918-1919 (Map-case folder 6-7)
- Scrapbooks, 1895-1949
  Nine scrapbooks consisting of articles, cartoons, certificates, clippings and other printed matter, editorials, letters of commendation, news releases, obituaries, official citations, patriotic message sent by Joseph W. Stilwell, personal letters, photographs, posters, programs, sketches, and telegrams relating to Joseph W. Stilwell's personal life and military service.
  - Clippings relating to Joseph W. Stilwell's recall, 1944; and maps and photos of Okinawa port facilities, 1945 July-August (Box 75)
  - Clippings relating to the Stilwell Road and to Joseph W. Stilwell as Commanding General of the U.S. Army ground forces, 1945 January-June (Box 76)
    Includes a letter from Gerald A. Koetting to Mrs. Joseph W. Stilwell, July 26, 1945.
  - Letters of commendation, photographs, telegrams, and clippings relating to the dedication of Stilwell Hall, Presidio of San Francisco, October 18, 1947 (Box 77)
  - Opinions of thirty American editors on the life and achievements of Joseph W. Stilwell, undated; posters and printed matter relating to the IV Army Corps, American Expeditionary Forces, 1918-1919; and representative newspaper stories and editorials on Joseph W. Stilwell, January-February 1945 (Box 78)
  - Articles about Joseph W. Stilwell, cartoons, certificates, clippings and other printed matter, letters, news releases, obituaries, official citations, patriotic message sent by Joseph W. Stilwell, photographs, posters, programs, sketches, and telegrams relating to Joseph W. Stilwell’s personal life and military service, 1895-1949 (Boxes 79-81)
- Lantern Slides, circa 1926-1939 (Boxes 82-85)
  253 slides depicting scenes of daily life and cultural sites in China.
- Photographs, 1899-1957
  7670 prints and postcards and 81 negatives depicting Joseph W. Stilwell, his family, career in the army, people and scenes in China, Europe, Japan, and the Philippines, and personalities, including Chiang Kai-shek, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Louis Mountbatten, and Winston Churchill.
  - 33 prints depicting award ceremony and dedication ceremonies for memorials for Joseph W. Stilwell, circa 1949 (Box-folder 86: A.1-4)
  - 11 prints depicting dedication ceremonies for Stilwell Field, 1946 November 11 (Box-folder 86: B.1-2)
  - 18 prints depicting dedication of Stilwell Dam and Lake at West Point, New York, 1949 July 26 (Box-folder 86: C.1-2)
  - 16 prints depicting dedication of Stilwell Park, Ft. Ord, California, 1957 September 7 (Box-folder 86: D.1-2)
  - 5 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell's gravestone, 1947 (Box-folder 86: E)
  - 20 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell as an observer of the Atomic bomb test at Bikini Island, 1946 July (Box-folder 86: F.1-2)
  - 43 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell at various informal and official functions while he was Commander of the 6th Army, Western Defense Command, San Francisco, California, 1946 (Box-folder 86: G.1-4)
  - 2 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell with Vice Admiral Jorge D. Martins, Brazilian Secretary of Navy, 1946 May 21 (Box-folder 86: H)
  - 55 prints depicting the surrender ceremony on the USS Missouri in Tokyo Bay, August 31, 1945, and of Joseph W. Stilwell's visit to Tokyo at the time (Box-folder 86: I.1-4)
  - 6 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell upon his return to the U.S. from his command of the 10th Army, Pacific Theater, 1945 October (Box-folder 86: J)